警告
接下來的節目包含劈砍
重擊及抽打僵尸的
可怕鏡頭
建議您在觀看前審慎考慮
另外  請勿在家
嘗試本片中的任何實驗
本片中所有的僵尸
均為專業人員
本集《流言終結者》為您呈現...
On this episode of "Mythbusters"...
警告
禁區  閑人免入
你看見什么了嗎
See anything?
僵尸  不死族
Zombies, the undead...
游蕩于世間  覓食人類大腦
Roaming the earth hunting for brains...
他們又找上門來了
They found us again.
長久以來人們都認為僵尸是虛構的
Long thought of as fictional...
都怪你和你那身臭雪茄味把它們引來了
It's you and your damn cigars.
好吧  可以確定不是你的大腦
Well, it sure ain't your brains.
他們確實是虛構的
Well, they are fictional.
但不代表我們不能進行和它們有關的實驗
That doesn't mean we can't test with them, though.
歡迎來到《流言終結者》僵尸特輯
Welcome to the "Mythbusters Zombie Special."
跟我喊  "大腦"
Say it with me, "Brains!"
跟我喊"大腦"啊
Say it with me, "Brains."
-大腦  -好  開始吧
-  Brains.  - There you go.
亡者們重見天日
The day of the dead has dawned.
我們共同集結  迎接末日的到來
Assembled for the apocalypse
同時《行尸走肉》里的滅僵大師
and joined by "The Walking Dead"'s
邁克爾·魯克也將加盟節目
master of mayhem, Michael Rooker...
我討厭僵尸
I hate zombies.
團隊將研究三條關于逃生的流言
The team tackles a trio of survival tall tales.
對抗僵尸法則一  瞄準腦袋
Rule number one -- ugh, aim for the head.
首先  在面對黑暗軍團的時候
First, when faced with the army of darkness,
斧頭...
Does the ax...
真的比槍更有效嗎
actually outgun the gun?
無可挑剔
Groovy.
然后  一群僵尸到底是怎么把門頂開的呢
Then, how exactly does an undead horde heave down a door?
我們來吃你了  老頭子
We're coming for you, old man.
最后
And finally,
僵尸真的能追上活人嗎
can walkers really outpace the human race?
被僵尸追趕時  你確實跑得更快
You do run faster when zombies are chasing you.
■
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
流言終結者是何方神圣
Who are the mybusters?
翻譯：cindysheva  超級大漢堡
亞當·沙維奇
Adam Savage...
科學概率70%
70% chance of science.
翻譯：雪莉的苦艾  拉面配鹵蛋  兮之
杰米·海曼
And Jamie Hyneman.
你鬧夠了沒
Are you done screwing around?
翻譯：死跑龍套的  杰森  Foxer
他們有超過三十年的特技經驗
Between them, more than 30 years of special-effects experience.
軸軸：雪貴人  小獄
和他們二位一道的是  托里·貝魯奇
Together with Tory Belleci...
來鋸了這輛車吧
Let's chop this car up!
校對：Wei2321L  萌Su
格蘭特·今原
Grant Imahara
有東西剛剛碰到我了
Something just touched me!
還有卡莉·拜倫
And Kari Byron.
后期：8T
應該會很有趣
This should be fun.
他們不光講述流言
They don't just tell the myths.
他們還將流言付諸實踐
They put them to the test.
流言終結者
僵尸特輯
準備好收看科幻小說里的科學事實吧
Stand by for some facts with your fiction.
本集是"流言終結者大戰僵尸"
It's "Mythbusters" Versus Zombies.
僵尸特輯
第一個流言是什么
What's up first?
我問你
Well, let me ask you.
如果你被僵尸群包圍了
If you were surrounded by a zombie horde
而你只能選擇一件武器的話
and you could choose only one weapon,
你會選哪個呢
what would you choose --
槍還是斧頭
the gun or the ax?
-當然是槍  -沒錯
- The gun. - Right.
大多數人都會這么選  但有一條流言說
Most people would, but there's a myth
其實斧頭是更好的選擇
that the ax is in fact the better tool.
-真的嗎  -是的  你看這樣行不
- Really? - Yeah. So what do you say?
你拿槍  我拿斧頭
You take the gun, I take the ax.
我們去找些僵尸來吧
Let's go find some zombies.
-僵尸是虛構的  -對哦
- Zombies are fictional.  - Right.
那就去找一百個扮演僵尸的人吧
Let's go find 100 people willing to dress as zombies.
-成  -這個不難辦吧
- Okay. - How hard could that be?
確實一點也不困難
As it turns out, not hard at all.
《流言終結者》迷們最愛變裝打扮
"Mythbusters" fans love getting dressed up.
亞當和杰米到底要怎樣
Now, how exactly are Adam and Jamie
在不傷害任何人的情況下
going to test the weapons' lethal efficiency
測試武器的殺傷效率呢
without actually hurting anybody?
既然杰米選擇了槍作為武器
Now, since Jamie's weapon of choice is a gun
而小說里說殺死僵尸的唯一方法
and the only fictional way to kill a fictional zombie
是爆頭
is with a headshot...
這意味著我們要對著僵尸志愿者的面部開槍
We're gonna need to shoot our zombie volunteers in the face,
因此我們必須想辦法保護
which means we're gonna have to protect the faces
僵尸志愿者的面部
of our zombie volunteers.
解決方案就是塑料面具
The answer is plastic face protectors...
我覺得應該有效
I think this is going to work.
并且使用彩彈槍
and paintball guns.
今天能好好玩一把了
This is gonna make my day.
沒錯  今天是"朝亞當的臉射擊"日
Yep. It's "shooting Adam in the face" day.
正中靶心
Bull's-eye!
杰米一槍正中我的眉心
Jamie hit me dead between the eyes
而帶著僵尸面具的我
while I was wearing my zombie mask,
沒什么感覺
and I didn't feel a thing,
完全達到了保護志愿者的目的
which is exactly what I want our volunteers to be feeling.
既然原型滿足要求
So, now, the prototype works.
我們要批量制作至少一百個這樣的面具
It's time to mass-manufacture at least 100 of these.
這些準備工作是為了讓杰米·海曼
All of this work just so that Jamie Hyneman
能夠為了科學目的  舉槍射擊陌生人的臉
can shoot strangers in the face for science!
接下來  亞當開始為流言中推薦的
Next, Adam turns to the myth-preferred method
殺死僵尸的方法做準備
for wasting walkers.
我覺得你們都同意
Now, I'm quite sure you all agree with me
我所選的消滅僵尸的武器  斧頭
that the weapon I've chosen for killing zombies, the ax,
會比槍好使得多
is far superior to the gun.
不過由于僵尸并不存在
But since zombies don't actually exist
我也不能用真的斧頭
and I won't be able to drive an actual ax
劈開他們可愛的頭骨
through their ever-loving undead skulls,
我必須找到一種安全殺死僵尸的方法
I'm gonna have to come up with a safe way for killing our zombies.
快看亞當的海綿斬首斧
Cue Adam's clever cushioned cleaver.
它可以安全地在砍到的每個僵尸腦袋上
It'll leave a safe green paint splatter
留下一道綠色顏料印記
for every zombie brain splattered.
這太贊了
Aw. This is awesome.
我昨晚填裝的彩彈顏料
The paintball paint that I put in the compartment last night
已經漂亮地滲進了泡沫里
has beautifully seeped through the foam.
看看它會留下怎樣的印記
Let's see what kind of mark it makes.
這就是已死僵尸的印記
That is the mark of one dead zombie,
雖然他們本來就已經死了
except that they're already dead.
姑且叫他們凍結僵尸好啦
Let's just call them inactive zombies.
趕緊去實驗吧
Let's get to testing!
武器準備就緒
And so, with weapons at the ready...
你會喜歡這里的
You'll like this place.
這是個慎人的好地方
It's nice and creepy.
終結者們集結在此絕佳之地
The team assembles at the perfect location
將僵尸消滅殆盡
for a spot of zombie annihilation.
為了測試哪個才是干掉僵尸最有效的方法
For testing the most efficacious method for dispatching a zombie,
用槍還是用斧頭
a gun or an ax,
我們來到了我們最愛的場地之一
we've come to one of our all-time favorite locations.
這里不僅夠大  能讓我們充分觀察
It's not only a big enough space for us to really see
了解實驗情況
and understand what's going on,
還有些后啟示錄的味道
it's suitably post-apocalyptic.
我感覺像是被一只爬行僵尸追著一樣
I feel like I'm being chased by a crawling zombie.
沒錯  腦子
Yeah! Brains!
人類
區域
如果我在躲避僵尸
If I was hiding out from zombies,
我就會選擇這樣的避難所
this is exactly the kind of citadel I would seek out.
■
僵尸
Zombies!
僵尸群
這里就是實驗場地了
That's the arena.
那么該如何運用它呢
Now, how will it be used?
實驗方法非常簡單直接
The methodology here is pretty straightforward.
我將站在這個直徑九多米的圓圈中
I'll be standing in the middle of a 30-foot-diameter circle.
這里是人類活動區域
That is the human zone.
僵尸將分散在建筑各處
The zombies will be dotted around the building
在綠色僵尸區域活動
in their green zombie zone.
現在當我們發出信號時
Now, when we give the signal,
僵尸們就會拖著僵尸步
they will start their zombie shuffle
向著分界線移動  過來
towards the line of demarcation. Come on!
在僵尸到達橙色線之前我們不能攻擊它
Now, we can't engage them until they reach that orange line,
不過一旦它們越線...
but once they do...
它們就任我們屠殺了
they're all ours.
對于殺光所有100個僵尸我不抱希望
I don't expect to make it through all 100 zombies.
但關鍵是我能殺多少
The question is, how far will I get?
大腦
Brains.
人類區域
對于我來說規則基本一樣
And the rules will be the same for me,
只是我的武器是槍
except I'm gonna be packing a gun.
砰
Bang.
大腦
Brains!
以上這些就是規則了
That's the rules and regulations.
但是實驗對象從哪里找呢
But how about the test subjects?
事實上  僵尸是虛構的
Now, let's be honest-- zombies are fictional,
這也意味著和它們打交道是不可能的
which means every way of dealing with them is also fictional.
為了對付僵尸  我們需要一位專家
As for how to dispatch them, we thought we needed an expert,
那么這個人選非邁克爾·魯克莫屬
So where better to go than the one and only Michael Rooker,
也就是《行尸走肉》中的莫爾·迪克森
A.K.A. Merle Dixon from "The walking dead"?
他將向杰米傳授他對付僵尸的
He is going to show Jamie some of his preferred methodologies
方法心得
for dispatching the undead.
邁克爾  關于對付僵尸有什么建議嗎
Michael, any advice on taking out zombies?
邁克爾·魯克
在AMC劇集《行尸走肉》中飾演莫爾
我注意到你有
Well, I noticed you have
一些不錯的武器
a couple of handy-dandy weapons here.
現在我需要一只僵尸
Well, all we need now is a zombie, I guess, huh?
僵尸我們也有不少
Well, we got plenty of those.
僵尸先生有請
Cue the undead man walking.
我知道了  多謝
I see. Well, thank you.
如果它們靠近  你可以先向膝蓋來一發
If they're approaching, you just pop them in the knee.
砰
Bang!
如果他們仍然向你靠近...
If they're still approaching...
就向另一個膝蓋也來一發
pop them in the other knee.
很明顯  他們非常饑餓...
Of course, they are kind of hungry...
而且他們有點
And they're a little...
好吧
Okay.
通常我會這樣把他們放倒抓住
Usually I grab them and hold them down like that,
然后爆頭
and I pop them in the head.
漂亮
Nice.
不要開門  內有僵尸
咻  干掉了一只僵尸
Phew! That's one down.
但為了測試哪種武器最適合
But to test which weapon is the most efficient
對付大群僵尸  我們就需要一大群
to deal with zombies en masse, we need a horde.
這個視角看太酷了
That is an awesome view.
為了實驗的精確
And for experimental accuracy,
他們要學學該如何移動
they need to know exactly how to move.
早上好  僵尸們
Good morning, zombies.
早上好
Morning!
不對  不對
Oh, no, no, no, no.
要像僵尸一樣  早上好  僵尸們
Like zombies! Good morning, zombies.
你們應該認識我右邊的這位先生
You might recognize this gentleman to my right,
來自《行尸走肉》中的邁克爾·魯克
Michael Rooker from "The walking dead."
現在邁克爾將教你們如何走僵尸步
Now, Michael is going to give you guys a lesson in the zombie shuffle.
憑借在《行尸走肉》中的表演經驗
Using all his "Walking dead" Experience,
邁克爾指導志愿者們如何演僵尸
Michael coaches the volunteers on zombie behavior.
愚笨緩慢地向著食物移動腳步...
An unintelligent, slow shuffle towards food...
好多了
Much better.
加上獨特的扭姿
with a unique twist.
很好  停
That's good. Cut.
非常好  你演的很嚇人
Okay. Very good. You're scary.
各位  你們要做出你們獨特的步伐
And, everybody, you got to develop your own walk.
他是一只僵尸  你們都是與眾不同的僵尸
He's an individual zombie. You're all individual zombies.
你們不是從一個模子里做出了的僵尸
You're not cookie-cutter zombies.
表現你的個性
Develop your own deal.
教學結束  僵尸們都出師了...
With the demonstration complete, school's out...
好  僵尸游行開始
All right, commence zombie shuffle now!
恐怖降臨
and the terror begins.
這的確很嚇人
That is positively terrifying.
沒錯
Yeah!
很高興他們現在還不餓
I'm happy they're not trying to eat me right now.
同意
Me, too.
隨著恐怖逼真的僵尸部落的集結
And with the horrifyingly realistic horde assembled...
聽那聲音
Listen to that sound.
是時候該開始實驗了
it's time to get down to experimental business.
僵尸們  準備好了嗎
All right. Zombies, are you ready?
亞當  你準備好了嗎
Adam, are you ready?
準備好了  先生
I'm ready, sir!
好  三  二  一
All right. Three, two, one.
去死
Gah! Dead!
Dead!
去死  去死
Dead! Dead!
啊  我掛了
Ah! I've been killed.
你現在成僵尸的盤中餐了  兄弟
You're zombie meat, brother.
我覺得我殺了不到20個
I don't think I killed more than 20.
我來數數
I'll count.
一  二  三  四  五...
One, two, three, four, five...
十一  十二  十三
eleven, twelve, thirteen.
只有13個嗎
Thirteen. That's it?
確實不多
That's not many.
即使在實驗中我只殺了13只僵尸
Even though I only killed 13 in that test,
我仍然覺得用斧頭當武器
I'm still feeling really good about the ax
是個不錯的選擇
as the weapon of choice.
去死  去死
Dead! Dead!
我真心覺得我的攻擊速度
I just feel that I can reload
比吉米用槍的速度要快
faster than Jamie will be able to with a gun.
我掛掉了
Ah! I've been killed.
為了確保實驗的準確性
Just to make sure that that test was accurate,
我需要讓僵尸群再出動一次
I'm gonna have the zombies brought out again.
我要做第二次嘗試
I'm gonna try a second time,
兩次結果取平均值
so we can average my results across both tests.
僵尸來襲倒數  三  二  一
All right. Zombies attack in three, two, one.
亞當能否憑借第一次測試獲得的經驗
Will Adam be able to use his knowledge from test one
來提高擊殺僵尸的數量呢
to improve his zombie count?
亞當身手矯健
He's a blur of action,
面對蹣跚吼叫著靠近的襲擊者們
holding off his creeping, moaning, and shuffling attackers
奮戰不懈
as long as he can.
然而  跟上次一樣  憑借絕對數量優勢
But, as before, by sheer weight of numbers,
蹣跚逼近的僵尸流
the encroaching slow-motion zombie tsunami
吞沒了我們的斧頭哥
overwhelms our ax-wielding hero.
我感覺我這次有了進步
I think I got further this time.
我覺得我的擊殺數增加了
I think I killed more.
確實  但著實有限
He did, but just barely.
我數的是15
I got 15.
我也是15
I got 15, as well.
那就是15個
15 it is.
平均起來  一共擊殺14個僵尸
Which is an average kill count of 14
不錯  成績相當穩定
And good, consistent data.
但是這個數字能贏過槍嗎
But will it outgun the gun?
接下來輪到海曼出場了
Up next is the Hyneman.
我先熱身熱身
I just want to get warmed up.
他可是認真的
And he means business --
認真擊殺僵尸
zombie-killing business.
妙哉
Groovy.
接下來在《流言終結者》中
Coming up on "Mythbusters",
我們將測試能否逃出僵尸大群的魔爪
we see if you can outrun a horde of zombies.
接下來
Up next,
遲緩的僵尸真的能捉住跑動的活人嗎
can the walking dead really catch the running living?
死亡競賽
每部僵尸片中
In every zombie movie,
都有僵尸群撲倒活人的場景
there is that scene where the horde descends on somebody,
然后將其大卸八塊
and just tears them to shreds.
現在我們要試其真偽
And that is the myth that we are going to be testing.
能不能逃出大群僵尸
Can you escape the zombie horde?
這是個我一直都在想的問題
Okay, this is one thing that I've always wondered about。
因為按常理來說
Because traditionally,
僵尸行走的時速大概只有三公里吧
don't they just shuffle at like 2 miles an hour?
感覺想擺脫他們不成問題
And it feels like you can just outrun them.
當然了
Well, yeah, sure,
擺脫一兩個大概沒什么問題
maybe you could outrun one or two no problem,
但是僵尸末日中怎么好意思只有幾個僵尸
but what zombie apocalypse only has a couple zombies?
我明白你的意思
Okay, I see what you're saying.
數量是關鍵因素  我們要測試這個
It's a numbers game, and that's what we're testing.
正是這樣
Exactly.
絕對將是史上最牛流言測試
This is gonna be the best myth ever.
僵尸群已經盯上了
The zombie horde has their undead eyes
活生生的人類
on the living prize.
盡管腐爛的身軀行動遲緩
But, despite shuffling at the speed of a decomposing corpse,
但手無寸鐵而腿腳靈便的人類
the result is somehow inevitable,
或許終究逃不過被抓住的命運
the unarmed fleet-footed humans always get caught,
然后腦子被吃掉
and it's a brain buffet.
你們想怎樣測試這個流言呢
How do you guys want to test this myth?
我們劃定一個區域
All right, well, let's set up an area,
比如橄欖球場那么大
say, the size of a football field,
然后安排一群僵尸在里面
and then get a zombie horde.
我們試試能否橫穿這個場地而不被抓住
We'll see if we could run through it and escape them.
就是說我們需要找一群僵尸
All right, well, that means we need some zombies,
還要弄清楚他們應該如何行動
and we need to figure out how they're supposed to behave.
我知道一個很合適的人  他是僵尸專家
Well, I know the perfect person who's an expert on zombies.
他能告訴我們  僵尸可以做什么不能做什么
He could tell us what they can and can't do,
同時還可以幫助我們設定實驗參數
and he'll help us set up the parameters for our myth.
聽起來不錯
Sounds good.
小分隊即將上演末日版奧林匹克
So, the team will stage the apocalyptic Olympics.
生存競速中人類將對抗僵尸群
It's humans versus the horde in a race for survival.
但首先  托里要拜見一位他的好萊塢偶像
But, first up, Tory's meeting one of his Hollywood heroes,
行尸界的傳奇   格雷格·尼克特洛
legend of the undead Greg Nicotero.
為了保證僵尸實驗的準確性
In order for us to test these zombie myths accurately,
我們要掌握更全面的資料
we need to get some more information.
為此  我們來到了KNB工作室
So, we're here at KNB studios,
這是一家特效工作室
a special-effects house.
所有恐怖片當中的僵尸
They are responsible for pretty much every zombie
活死人之日
鬼玩人2
猛鬼街5：猛鬼怪胎
鬼玩人3
夜驚魂
殺出個黎明
殺死比爾
罪惡之城
活死人之地
隔山有眼
死亡證據
朽木
死亡日記
無恥混蛋
死人島
絕命毒師
被解放的姜戈
基本上都出自這里
you've ever seen in any horror movie,
行尸走肉
更不用提熱播劇  《行尸走肉》了
Not to mention the show "Walking dead."
我們現在要去找格雷格·尼克特洛
So, we're gonna go talk to Greg Nicotero right now,
他幾乎可以算是僵尸之王了
who is pretty much the king of zombies,
一定能給我們提供有用信息
and get a little bit more information.
我們的實驗需要一些僵尸的資料
We need some zombie data to test our myth.
我們想更加深入地了解僵尸
We just need to know a little bit more about zombies
包括他們能做什么  不能做什么
and what they can and can't do.
我們以《活死人之夜》中墓地的一幕
We used the scene in "Night of living dead" in the cemetery
格雷格·尼克特洛
AMC電視臺《行尸走肉》特效化妝師
作為我們設定
as our sort of holy grail
僵尸活動規律的準則
for zombie movement.
行動緩慢  三公里每小時
他們不是很快
They're not very quick.
會被聲音吸引過去
They're attracted to sound.
會被聲音及食物吸引
某些時候光或黑暗也會吸引他們
I think sometimes they're attracted to light or dark.
沒有認知能力
還有他們十分呆滯
I don't think they're very smart.
總的說來  你只需要確保
Generally speaking, you just got to make sure
不會被一大群僵尸困住就行
that you don't get overrun by too many of them.
我們已經掌握了實驗的相關原則
So, armed with the experimental rules of engagement...
僵尸世界末日
All right, zombie apocalypse.
我們快到了
We're almost there.
小分隊在末日爆發點集結
the team assembles at apocalypse ground zero.
僵尸世界末日  前方1.6公里
我要換上僵尸殺手帽
Need my zombie-killing hat.
我們來到了阿拉米達跑道
We are here at the Alameda runway
來驗證活人跑不過僵尸群的說法
to test the myth that you can't outrun a zombie horde.
實驗的步驟是這樣的
Now, the way we're gonna test this
我們將打造僵尸末日當中
is we're gonna create a part of a city
已經淪陷的城市一角
that has been overrun by the zombie apocalypse.
僵尸
現在  只差一大群僵尸登場了
Now all we need is a zombie horde.
我們找到了150名志愿者來扮演僵尸
So we have 150 volunteers for our zombie horde.
我的娘呀
Oh, my god!
僵尸群出現了
Here comes the horde.
這個數目再合適不過了
Now, for us, that is the perfect number
在這片指定區域里面
Because in our designated area,
全部的志愿者正好對應
all of those volunteers represent
曼哈頓的人口密集度
a population density of Manhattan.
那就是每平方公里3.5萬人口
That's 90,000 people per square mile.
待會他們會分散到場地中
We're gonna scatter them around the field
然后我們將嘗試從場地一端跑到另一端
and try and run from one end to the other.
我們會將這些小型大腦背在背上
We'll be wearing these mini brains on our backs.
如果他們抓住了其中一個
If they manage to grab one of these,
那就意味著我們突圍失敗
that means that we haven't escaped the horde.
也就是說  我們被吃掉了
It means that we've been eaten.
現在  該把僵尸引過來了
So, now, it's time to bring on the zombies.
簡直太嚇人了
This is freaking me out.
我一點也不喜歡這個
I don't like this at all.
這真可怕
This is terrifying.
這是他們想要的僵尸群
Well, they asked for a zombie horde.
有一些基本原則
Now, some ground rules.
歡迎你們  僵尸們
Welcome, zombie horde!
原則一
Rule number one,
僵尸們只能慢速移動
zombies can only move at a slow shuffle.
原則二
Rule number two,
你們的大腦被感染了
your brains are infected,
所以你們不會理性思考
so you have no rational thought.
原則三
Rule number three,
這就是你們的目標
this is your target.
大腦
Brains!
開始搶奪大腦吧
Let the brains begin!
基于保障數據可靠性的行為準則
With a code of conduct established for consistent data,
我再也不想玩這個了
I don't want to do this anymore.
這些僵尸在實驗場地上隨機分散開來
the animated deceased disperse randomly over the experimental space...
實  驗  場  地
實驗場地長91米
A field of play 100 yards long
僵尸150只
寬50米  我們人類必須穿越場地
and 55 yards wide that our humans have to cross
同時保證大腦完好無損
while keeping their brains intact.
第一個代表活人出場的是卡莉
And first up to race for the human race is Kari.
不得不說  我有點緊張
I have to say, I'm kind of nervous.
首先
First of all,
那邊那個女孩看起來像是真的要吃了我
that girl right there looks like she's actually going to eat me.
我不知道我能不能成功
I don't know if I'm gonna make it through.
僵尸出場后我感覺沒有之前想的那么簡單
It looked a lot easier before the zombies showed up.
出發吧
All right. Let's go.
格蘭特和托里躲在高處觀察
So with Grant and Tory observing from a safe overhead distance,
游戲開始了
let the games begin.
她出發了
There she goes.
這個奪取大腦的游戲的關鍵在數字上
At the heart of this brain game are the numbers.
一個活人對抗150只僵尸
It's 1 human versus a zombie horde of 150.
我的天吶  太可怕了
Oh, my god. That is terrifying.
卡莉以16公里的時速迂回躲閃
And Kari is dodging and weaving at 10 miles an hour,
而僵尸們只能以三公里的時速追趕
while the walkers can only chase at 2.
她看起來很不錯  她要成功了
She's looking good. She's gonna make it.
你看起來不錯
You look great.
不可能
No way.
她會成功的  加油  加油
Yeah, she's gonna make it. Come on. Come on.
這些數字因素...
And those numbers...
她成功了
She made it!
幫助卡莉成功生存
add up to Kari's survival.
被僵尸追趕時  你確實跑得更快
You do run faster when zombies are chasing you.
卡莉毫無疑問的在僵尸中生存下來了
Kari survived the zombie horde no problem.
但是你知道嗎  我們下面要做的就是
But you know what? The next thing we're gonna do
是將僵尸群密度增加50%
is increase the population density by 50%.
這一次  輪到托里了
And this time, it's Tory's turn.
實驗場地縮小了
So the field of play is reduced in size...
縮小了23米[其實密度增加了33%]
25 yards in.
這意味著僵尸的密度增加到
meaning the zombie density is increased
每平方公里5.2萬人
to 135,000 per square mile,
與印度大城市孟買部分地區人口密度相同
matching parts of the massive Indian megacity Mumbai.
希望你喜歡意大利菜
I hope you like Italian food!
天吶
Oh, boy.
僵尸的密度達到了泛濫的程度
The apocalypse has reached epidemic proportions.
你們準備好了嗎
You guys ready?
準備好了就說一聲
Ready when you are.
快跑  托里  快跑
Run, Tory, run!
躲開
Dodge.
從旁邊饒  干得好
Weave. Good job!
僵尸們顯然變得更密集了
The zombies are clearly more densely packed.
而托里變相重新體驗了一次高中橄欖球之夢
But Tory, reliving a twisted version of his high-school football dreams,
最后安全抵達終點
makes it to the end zone safely.
-我的天吶  -他成功了
- Oh, my god.  - He made it!
他成功了
He made it!
我的大腦還齊全嗎
Do I have all my brains?
是的
Yes.
我成功穿過了僵尸群  并且大腦都健在
So I made it through the zombie horde with all my brains intact,
這簡直太瘋狂了
and it was insane!
我的腎上腺素都升高了
The adrenaline was flowing.
僵尸們想吃掉我
The zombies were trying to eat me,
但我度過了這個難關
but I made it through.
現在  我們要再進行一次
But now we're gonna do it again.
這一次  我們要將僵尸密度增加更多
This time, we're gonna increase the population density even more.
這一次  該輪到格蘭特了
This time, Grant's gonna go for it.
人類無法躲避一群僵尸的流言
The myth that you can't elude a legion of living dead
貌似要被終結了
is looking deceased.
快跑
Quick!
但我們還要將一位主持人送入僵尸群
But there's one more host to offer the horde
還有一個變量需要調整
and one variable to adjust,
僵尸
密度
density.
我們下面要做的就是將密度增加到
So what we're gonna do next is increase that
每平方公里7萬人
to 180,000 people per square mile,
這是世界上人口最密集的地區
which is the most densely populated area in the world.
下一個就該我了
And I'm up next.
接下來《流言終結者》
Coming up next on "Mythbusters"...
救命啊
Help!
殺死僵尸的最佳方法是什么
發送#殺死僵尸  將你與僵尸戰斗的妙方
通過推特分享給杰米和亞當
《流言終結者》
僵尸特輯
大家好  我是邁克爾·魯克
Hi, everybody. This is Michael Rooker.
歡迎回到《流言終結者》僵尸特輯
And welcome back to the "Mythbusters zombie special."
我討厭僵尸
I hate zombies.
他來到了正確的地方
Well, he's come to the right place
因為亞當和杰米正在驗證
because Adam and Jamie are testing the myth
在殺死僵尸方面
that when it comes to wasting walkers...
去死  去死
Dead! Dead!
斧子比槍更有效的流言
ax trumps gun.
我已經用斧子對付了一群僵尸
I have already confronted a zombie horde with an ax,
我能在他們取得我的大腦前
and I was able to down 14 of their undead brethren
砍死14具僵尸
before they got to my brains.
現在該輪到拿著槍的杰米了
Now it's Jamie's turn to do the same with a gun
看他能否超越我
and see if he can do any better.
我們的僵尸們都裝備防具了
Well, our zombies are all properly protected.
你準備好要向他們的臉射擊了嗎
You ready to shoot some in the face?
-開始吧  -好的
- Bring it on.  - Okay.
祝你好運  但愿你能突破14
Good luck. I hope you get more than 14.
現在就讓我們拭目以待
It's time to find out.
杰米和他的單發手槍
Jamie and his single-action handgun
對戰食腦僵尸大軍
versus a legion of brain-eating zombies.
結果是
And...
食腦僵尸大軍獲勝
The legion of brain-eating zombies wins...
救命
Help!
毫無疑問
Convincingly.
海曼的成績  25秒
So, Hyneman's score -- 25 seconds...
-殺死6個僵尸  -不怎么樣啊
- Six zombies.  - Not a very good score.
真慘
Sad.
看著真的很精彩
That was really stunning to watch.
從我的經驗來說
I can tell you from experience,
站在那里  看著所有人
it's creepy to be in there
向你蹣跚而來的時候  相當嚇人
while everyone is shambling towards you.
他環顧四周
And he's doing this kind of looking back and forth.
氣氛相當緊張
It's real tension.
轉瞬之間  差不多4秒之后
And then all of a sudden, like four seconds later,
圈里就全是僵尸了
the entire circle is full of zombies
海曼就陣亡了
and the Hyneman went down.
現在他正準備來第二輪
Now, he's gonna go for a second run,
這一次他要調整裝備
and he's gonna be a little more prepared for this one.
我很期待他會帶來些什么
I can't wait to see what he comes up with.
他帶來了更多的槍
What he comes up with are more guns,
更多的子彈  更拉風
More ammo, and more style.
這次我全副武裝
This time, I'm loaded for bear.
腿上綁了兩把槍  腰上別了兩把槍
I've got two on the legs, two on the waist,
背后背了兩把槍  手上還有一把
two on the shoulders, one in the hand.
我的子彈足夠給這一百只僵尸每只來兩發
I've got 2 bullets for every one of these 100 zombies.
整裝待發
I'm ready as I'll ever be.
槍支對戰僵尸
Guns versus zombie.
倒數三  二  一
Three, two, one.
這次杰米用的是壓氣式彩彈槍
This time, Jamie has a pump-action paintball rifle
可以提高填裝子彈速度
that he can reload much faster.
開局很順利
And he starts well,
面對僵尸英勇奮戰
working his way through the walkers
效率比第一次有顯著提升
much more efficiently than his first test.
6  7  8
Six. Seven. Eight.
但還是不夠快
But it's still not nearly quick enough.
我試圖在周圍堆起一道尸體圍墻
I was trying to build a wall of zombies around me
這樣就可以阻擋其他人的進攻
so that I could keep these guys away from me,
結果我被一個僵尸絆住了
but I tripped on one
然后再次被吞沒了
and then I'm into the soup again.
我還是只殺死了  這是幾個  八個
And I still only got -- what is this, eight?
沒錯  八個
Yeah, eight.
這就是我在陣亡前
That's how many shots I can get off
能擊殺的數目了
before they're on me.
結果出來了
Well, that's a result!
結果再明顯不過了
And the result couldn't be clearer.
與機動靈活的斧子手亞當相比
Compared to a mobile, ax-wielding Adam,
杰米花了太多時間在上子彈  瞄準
it takes Jamie too long to reload, steady, take aim,
向僵尸射擊上
and take out the walkers.
數字說明了一切
The numbers don't lie.
你們覺得呢  最終比分如何
So, what do you think? What's the final tally?
平均下來  我只殺了7個
Well, my average was just over seven kills.
我殺了14個
Mine was 14 kills.
-兩倍  -兩倍
- Double. - Double.
斧子獲勝
Ax wins.
至少比單發手槍和壓氣槍有用
At least with single-action or pump shotgun.
-沒錯  -結果出來了
- Sure. - Well, that settles it.
斧子獲勝
Yeah. Ax wins.
近戰武器是王道
Bladed weapons rule.
證明了斧子是
And with the ax confirmed
末日武器的首選之后
as the apocalyptic weapon of choice...
這是他們努力工作的獎賞
This is their reward for the hard work.
僵尸們
Zombies!
-大腦  -該吃飯了
- Brains! - It's chow time.
流言證實
故事影片告訴我們
Filmic folklore suggests
盡管只能以三公里的時速挪動
that despite an average speed of just 2 miles an hour,
僵尸群卻總能抓到獵物
the zombie horde always gets its prey.
但卡莉和托里都已成功地
But with Kari and Tory already successful
從僵尸群中逃脫
in evading the zombie shuffle,
輪到格蘭特來保護自己的大腦不被吃掉了
It's Grant's turn to try and keep his brains intact.
他們很餓的樣子
They look hungry.
他要面對的是地球上最密集的人群
He's facing the highest population density on the planet,
每平方公里近七萬人
an incredible 180,000 people per square mile.
這是最糟糕的都市災難情節
It's the worst-case urban-apocalypse scenario
也是驗證流言的最后機會
And the last chance for the myth.
但他并沒有成功
But he just can't make it through.
不要
No!
一個走位失誤  他就被圍殲了
One mistake, and he's down and swarmed.
僵尸太多了
There's too many!
卡莉成功地從密度相當于
So Kari succeeded in outrunning a horde
曼哈頓人口密度的僵尸群中逃了出來
that was the population density of manhattan.
托里面對的僵尸密度要高些
Tory succeeded at a slightly higher population density
大概每平方公里五萬多人
of 135,000 people per square mile.
不幸的是  當僵尸密度達到
Unfortunately, when we got that density up to
每平方公里近七萬人的時候
180,000 people per square mile,
量變產生質變
that's where it all fell apart,
我無法從僵尸大軍中逃脫
and I could not escape the horde.
當僵尸大軍
When the horde
在市區中大量聚集的時候
is in a tightly packed urban environment,
速度慢不是問題
it doesn't matter that they're slow.
流言懸而未解  下一步該如何呢
So with the myth back in the balance, what next?
我們要用其它辦法
We're gonna try to come up with other tactics
試圖騙過僵尸  看能否讓我們逃脫
to try to trick the zombie horde and see if we can escape.
末日的第二天早晨
So day two of the dead dawns,
隊伍再次聚集起來
And the team once again rendezvous
試圖逃出這場大災難
in an attempt to outrun the apocalypse.
這次  他們每個人都準備了一個方案
And this time, they're each packing a plan.
畢竟  末日來臨的時候
After all, when the end is nigh,
有一個逃生計劃很關鍵
A good survival strategy is essential.
好了  卡莉
All right, Kari.
你要用什么  強力膠帶嗎
What's your technique, duct tape?
你用那個怎么對付僵尸呢
How's that gonna save you from a zombie horde?
我本來想裝瘸什么的
I was thinking maybe like a limp or something.
那倒是個好主意
Oh, that's good.
但我想到這樣會更有效
But then I thought that this would be so much better.
你要干...
What the...
等一下  這是要怎樣
Wait, what is this technique?
不要
No!
僵尸們
Hey, zombies!
有好吃的
Zombie food!
不要啊
No! No!
這是經典的誘導轉向法
It's a classic bait and switch,
這是莫爾可能會使用的策略
the type of tactic Merle might deploy.
莫爾·迪克森  電視劇《行尸走肉》中的反派角色
輪椅上的免費大餐分散了僵尸們的注意力
With the horde distracted by a free meal on wheels...
卡莉  你個...
Kari, you son of a...
卡莉借機逃之夭夭
Kari makes a run for it
成功抵達終點  重獲自由
and makes it to the end zone and freedom.
我活下來了
I live!
她自私地犧牲隊友的行為
Her cynical use of collateral damage...
多謝你啊  卡莉  賣得一手好隊友
Thanks a lot, Kari. Way to throw me under the bus.
為自己爭取了足夠多的時間
means she bought herself enough time
避免了腦子被僵尸吃掉
to avoid being lobotomized.
僵尸啟示錄
Zombie apocalypse,
這里可沒有友情這一說
the rules of friendship do not apply.
如果你有敵人  或是可以犧牲的同伴
If you have an enemy or co-worker to sacrifice,
借此擺脫僵尸  應該可行
escaping the horde may be possible.
接下來  《流言終結者》
Coming up on "Mythbusters",
有什么東西可以阻擋僵尸群嗎
can anything stop a zombie horde?
記住  孩子們
Remember, kids,
請勿在家嘗試本片中的任何實驗
don't try anything you're about to see at home.
沒錯  我們是專家
That's right. We're experts.
為什么說我們是專家呢
And why are we experts?
-腦子  -沒錯
- Brains! - That's right.
流言終結者
僵尸特輯
接下來將為您呈現僵尸們的力量
Up next, it's the might of the living dead.
強力一推
接下來講什么
What's up next?
僵尸的團隊合作
Zombie teamwork.
僵尸才不搞什么團隊合作
Zombies don't do teamwork.
-他們笨死了  -是的
- They're dead stupid. - Right.
僵尸不靠相互交談進行合作
Zombies don't talk to each other to do teamwork.
但他們都有共同的本能
But they do all have a common instinct,
這意味著他們通常共同合作
and that means they often work together.
僵尸電影里總有這樣的場景
You see it in zombie movies all the time.
主人公躲在被堵上的大門后面
Our heroes are barricaded behind some kind of big door,
僵尸們知道門后有美味的腦子
and the zombies know that there are brains behind that door.
于是它們都聚到一起
And they all gather up.
它們使勁推門  使勁推門
And they're pushing at the door, and they're pushing at the door.
最終  它們使用身體的力量
And eventually, through the force of all of their bodies,
把門打破了
they break the door down.
你像是在說
So, what you're saying is sort of like
死人多力量大
many dead hands make for light work.
是活死人多力量大
Many undead hands make for light work,
我覺得咱們應該驗證一下
and I think we should test that.
當然
Sure.
僵尸來襲
這是經典僵尸電影的俗套情節
It's a classic living-dead cliche.
立即撤離
美餐就在門后
Dinner's on the far side of a door,
絕望的生者倉促地把門窗釘死
a barrier hastily barred by the desperate living,
然而  僵尸們雖然毫無配合
and yet the uncoordinated efforts
卻能意外地讓力量匯集起來
of a zombie horde somehow combine
成功頂破大門
to successfully bust down the door.
問題是  這群僵尸真的壓倒一切嗎
Question is, does a mob really rule,
還是這只是小說中才有的物理現象
or is this physical-force fiction?
為了找出真相
To find out,
亞當和杰米來到一處相對偏遠的外景地
Adam and Jamie head for a suitably remote location
驗證人類對抗逼近的僵尸大軍的最后一戰
to test humanity's last stand against the approaching apocalypse.
瞧瞧
Look at that.
我身后的這座谷倉有153年的歷史了
The barn I'm standing in front of is 153 years old.
沒錯
That's right.
它建成的時候杰米還沒出生呢
It was built when Jamie was but a wee lad,
這道門就是我們和僵尸們的
and this door is the line of engagement
交戰地點
between us and the zombies.
在這里  我們將背水一戰
It's where we will have our last stand.
好了  完美
There we go. Perfect.
我們不想對這座漂亮的建筑造成任何損傷
Now, we don't want to hurt any part of this beautiful artifact,
因此我們實際上不會使用建筑物的門
so we're not actually gonna use their door,
我們甚至不會使用他們的谷倉
and we're not even gonna use their barn.
我們要在門框里搭一座鋼制框架
We're gonna build a steel frame within this doorframe
在框架里安裝我們的門
that we will attach our doors to
用來進行僵尸實驗
for proper zombie testing.
門挺時髦呀
Stylish doors.
看起來真不錯
They look great.
搬出死者
Bring out your dead!
倫敦大瘟疫時大量民眾染病死亡  收尸人沿街高喊"搬出死者"  將收集來的尸體統一埋葬
說起死者  亞當將加入到僵尸隊伍中
Speaking of dead, Adam will be joining team zed,
但他可不想真的喪命
but he doesn't want to actually die.
因此  在這個測試僵尸群力量
So in an experiment designed to test the forces of a crowd
能否打破牢牢釘緊的門的實驗中
crushing up against a securely bolted door,
嚴格的安全措施是必要的
serious safety measures are required.
如果你讓一百個人
If you take 100 people
去推一個固定不動的物體
and have them pushing against an immovable object,
如果每個人施加的推力
and if each one of them is able to exert
大概有220牛頓
something like 50 pounds of push,
合起來就有兩萬多牛頓
that totals about 5,000 pounds of pressure.
為了解決這個問題  我們想到了這個
So with that in mind, we've come up with this as a solution.
來撞一個
Belly bump.
這是聚乙烯波紋管
These are polyethylene corrugated sewer pipes.
你可能還記得它的初次登場
Now, you may recall seeing them first
在《流言終結者》"浣熊大炮"那集
on "Mythbusters" in "Raccoon rocket",
我們用它做過炮筒
where we used them as cannon barrels.
浣熊大炮S01E07
天吶
Oh, my god!
它們很輕巧  而且特別結實
They're light, and they're super strong,
應該能達到我們想要的效果
and they should do the trick.
與此同時
Meanwhile,
亞當被咬了然后變成僵尸了
Adam's been bitten and turned.
或者他只是逼真地化裝成了僵尸
Or he's had an extreme undead makeover.
與杰米一起參加僵尸來襲日大門對決的
Joining Jamie for the "Z"-day door duel...
我討厭僵尸
I hate zombies.
是邁克爾·魯克
is Michael Rooker...
來呀  想嘗嘗我的厲害嗎
Come on! You want some of this?
進來拿吧
Come and get it!
他似乎入戲變成了
who seems to have reverted
在《行尸走肉》中扮演的角色  莫爾·迪克森
to his "Walking Dead" character, Merle Dixon.
來呀
Come on!
就是這樣
This is it.
每人200牛頓方向不一的推力
Will the individuals' random 50-pound push force
能夠聯合起來形成共同作用力嗎
somehow combine at a coordinated point of pressure?
這股力量足以打破谷倉大門的橫擋板嗎
and will that be enough to break the barn door cross brace?
也許咱們退后一點比較好
Maybe we better back up a little bit.
好主意
I think that's a good idea.
情況不妙
This is not good!
咱們現在怎么辦  杰米
What do we do now, Jamie?
我都沒減速
I never even slowed down.
你們需要一個更堅固的門
You're gonna need a stronger door.
大家都沒事吧
Is everybody okay?
我就說我討厭僵尸
Told you I hated zombies.
輕而易舉地破門而入
Went right through that door, no effort at all.
作為實驗中僵尸大軍的一員
Being on the zombie side of the equation for this experiment,
太棒了  我在戰爭中選擇了陣營
fantastic because I'm choosing a side in this battle,
但不是活人這邊
but it's not with the living.
我的僵尸弟兄們跟著我來到門邊上
I reached that door with my zombie brethren behind me,
我甚至都沒停下腳步
and I don't think I actually even broke stride.
我推了門  僵尸們推著我
I touched the door, zombies touched me,
然后"呼啦"一下子  我們破門而入
and "Whoomp", we were through,
直奔杰米而去
and we were headed for Jamie.
那感覺太棒了
That was stunning.
我迫切地想知道一個更結實的門
Can't wait to see what a stronger door
會給我們帶來怎樣的挑戰
gives us in terms of challenge.
有了以上的結果
With a mixed body bag of results,
逃出僵尸包圍
the myth that out-running
而非火力鎮壓僵尸群的流言尚無定論
rather than outgunning a zombie horde is up for grabs.
有好吃的
Zombie food!
卡莉成功利用誘餌吸引了僵尸注意力
Kari managed to distract with a decoy,
下一位是格蘭特
but up next is Grant.
你可能已經猜到了  他是有備而來的
And as you might expect, he came prepared.
你要呆在這里面嗎
Are you gonna be inside this?
不  我的替身會
No. My double will.
對他而言
As far as he's concerned,
避免被滅的方法就是
when it comes to evading the apocalypse,
借助機器人的力量
robots are the answer.
這是我分散僵尸注意力的辦法
So this is my zombie-distraction technique.
沒錯  就像其他方法一樣
Now, yes, it's gonna employ distraction
它也是用來吸引僵尸的  但有幾點不同
just like the others, but it's a little bit different.
這臺機器能發光和聲音
This is a robot that has light and sound.
而且還有一個長得像我的假人在里面
And it's going to have a mannequin that looks like me.
格蘭特的方法很復雜
So, Grant has a very complex strategy here.
當我準備好時  我打開燈
When I'm ready to deploy, I'll turn on the lights,
打開音響
turn on the sound.
它會像我一樣叫喊
It's gonna scream just like me.
它看上去和我一模一樣
It's gonna look just like me.
會把所有僵尸都吸引過去
And it's gonna draw all the zombies over there,
然后我就跑向另一邊
And I'll run the other way.
你好啊  僵尸們
Hello, zombies!
我在這里
Here I am.
來吃我吧
Come and get me!
我的腦子美味又多汁
My brain is juicy and delicious.
格蘭特計劃的非常好
And Grant plays it perfectly,
等到所有聽到聲音的僵尸
Waiting until all the zombies within hearing distance
都被吸引過去后
are sucked in...
又多汁
and delicious.
快來抓我吧
Come and get me.
當他最終決定開跑的時候
So that when he finally makes a run for it,
他可以暢通無阻地沖向自由的彼岸
he has a clear path to freedom.
我成功了
I made it!
第一天  格蘭特沒成功
The first day, Grant didn't quite make it,
所以他比我們都更想讓這個
So he had more motivation than any of us
分神大法成功
to make this distraction work.
結果非常地有效
And it worked really, really well.
我的腦子美味又多汁
My brain is juicy and delicious.
來吃我吧
Come and get me.
十足的格蘭特風格
He did it Grant style.
他帶來了一臺又閃又吵的機器人
He pulled out a robot with lights and noise and yelling.
所有的僵尸都撲了過去
All of the zombies horded in on it,
格蘭特能從旁邊偷跑出去  獲得自由
And Grant could sneak around the side and get to freedom.
我成功了
I made it!
現在輪到托里了
So it's Tory's turn.
在他拜訪格雷格·尼克特洛的時候
And back when he visited Greg Nicotero,
他聽了一節大師級僵尸化妝課
he had a zombie makeover master class...
大功告成了
It looks like you're done.
這讓他想到了
That gave him the idea
通過偽裝來欺騙僵尸們的辦法
for his deceitful distraction technique.
看我能不能混進去
Let's see if I can blend in with them.
托里的計劃是混入僵尸群中
Tory is attempting to hide in plain sight.
在僵尸分散開前  他躲在一個汽車廢墟內
Before the zombies dispersed, he hid in one of the car wrecks.
在完成他全部的路程前
Now he has to get back to the start line
他必須要先回到起點
before completing his lap of the field.
志愿者能發現這名裝扮成僵尸的活人嗎
Will the volunteers recognize the human dressed as a zombie?
他血淋淋腐爛的傷口偽裝能經得住考驗嗎
Will his bloody, decomposing disguise stand up to scrutiny?
托里已經回到這里了
Tory's made it all the way here.
什么
What?
他已經回到這里了  而且
He's made it all the way here, and is --
-在哪里  -他在往回走了
- Where? - He's heading back.
但離終點線還有一半的時候
But halfway to the finish line...
他被發現了
he's discovered.
壞菜了
Oh! No!
我死了
I'm dead!
退后  退后
Back! Back!
退后  僵尸們
Back, zombies!
-退后  退后  -崩  崩
- Back! Back! - Fire! Fire!
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
一開始還有效
Well, it kind of worked at first.
我成功了混進了僵尸群
I mean, I was able to sneak through the horde,
但當那只僵尸認出我的時候
But then at one point, a zombie recognized me,
一切都結束了
and then it was all over.
他們全都撲上來了
They were all onto me.
但沒關系  只要我們一個人
But it doesn't matter because as long as one of us
成功地穿過僵尸群
made it through in one experiment,
就表示注意力分散有用  流言被終結了
that means it works and it's busted.
沒錯
That's right.
分散注意力的方法能夠幫助你逃離僵尸群
Distraction is a technique that allows you to escape the horde.
流言被終結了
This myth is busted.
完全被終結
Totally busted.
終結  可以說整個團隊
Busted, and you could say the team is, uh,
都因此結果而顫栗了
thriller-ed with the result.
邁克爾·杰克遜的著名歌曲
我剛聽說我們要測試關于僵尸的流言時
When I first heard that we were gonna test zombie myths,
我有兩個反應
I had two reactions.
第一個是  天啊  一定會超贊的
One was, "Oh, my god. This is the best day ever."
但是我下一個反應是
But then, my next reaction was,
我們要如何科學地做這個測試
"How are we gonna test this scientifically?"
但我們最終的確得到了一些結果
But we actually came away with some results.
要成功穿越很不容易
Now, it was difficult,
而且僵尸越密集就越難
and the more condensed they got,
直到完全不可能穿越它們
the harder it became till it was impossible.
然而格蘭特想出了引開僵尸群的
However, Grant did figure out a way to distract the horde
逃生方法  所以流言被終結了
in order to escape, so it's busted.
我已經很久沒有玩的這么開心了
This is the most fun I've had in so long.
流言終結
貝魯奇博士的僵尸寶典
僵尸是什么
流言終結者教學錄像
What is a zombie?
僵尸是一種無腦
A zombie is a mindless,
對人肉饑渴的復活死尸
reanimated corpse with the hunger for human flesh.
如何殺死僵尸
How to kill a zombie --
僵尸本來就死了  所以無法殺死它們
You cannot kill a zombie, for they are already dead.
但你可以通過摧毀它們的大腦來阻止它們
But you can stop them by destroying the brain.
有些人誤以為僵尸只吃腦子
One misconception about zombies is that they only eat brains,
但僵尸對人身上的所有地方都感興趣
but zombies have an appetite for all human flesh.
怎么樣會被僵尸傳染
How to be infected by a zombie --
最常見的傳染方式是被僵尸咬到
The most common way of infection is through a bite from a zombie.
如果你遇到僵尸
If you do encounter a zombie,
馬上逃跑并迅速聯系當地政府部門
run away and contact your local authorities immediately.
《流言終結者》
僵尸特輯
一大群僵尸真的能
Is it true that a mass of zombies
將推力聚合  沖破大門嗎
can combine their push pressure into a door-busting force?
杰米  莫爾
Jamie, Merle...
來吧  你想來點這個嗎
Come on! You want some of this?
野蠻的僵尸之王亞當和他的僵尸們
And savage head of the undead Adam...
即將來檢驗流言
are attempting to find out.
目前為止  與這扇門不同
So far, unlike the door...
這則流言暫時撐住了門面
this movie myth is bearing up.
杰米  快逃
Jamie, go now!
但是幸存者們可不會束手就擒
But our human survivors aren't going down without a fight.
假設他們的藏身處并非一個搖搖欲墜的舊谷倉
Suppose their hideout wasn't such a rickety old barn.
杰米  你覺得這扇新門怎么樣
So, Jamie, what do you think about this new door?
比上一個要堅固多了
Well, it's a lot tougher than the last one.
這扇門夠結實
This is a proper gate.
所有主要結構件拐角處
It's got carriage bolts at the corners
都裝有螺栓
of all the main structural members.
必須要把什么東西撞斷
Something is gonna have to snap
才有可能通過這個門
for them to make it through that.
好的  亞當
Okay, Adam.
真壯觀啊
Huh, what a sight.
停
Halt.
我們來了  老家伙
We're coming for you, old man.
準備好  三  二  一
Here we go! Three, two, one.
推
Push!
改進后的新門也完全不夠堅固
The new and improved door isn't nearly strong enough.
停  僵尸們  我們贏啦
Halt! Zombies, we made it!
老家伙裝了一扇更堅固的門...
但是我們還是成功通過了
他死定了
還沒完  因為杰米另備有
Not quite, because Jamie has something
可以驗證或終結流言的妙計
up his sleeve that's make-or-break for this myth,
真的
literally.
情況是這樣的
So here's the scenario.
有100個饑餓的僵尸在追你
You've got 100 hungry zombies after you.
你躲在一個谷倉里
You've got a barn to hide in,
我們已經證明了
and we've already shown that
如此多數量的僵尸可以產生
that many zombies can exert an enormous amount of pressure
極大的推力
on something they push against.
那怎么辦呢
So what are you gonna do?
電影里的招數是
What they do in the movies
找到所有能用的木板
is they grab every spare piece of lumber they can find
然后把它們全部釘在門和窗戶上
and they nail it all over the doors and windows.
我信不過那些門軸
I don't trust those hinges.
這正是我們要做的
That's what I'm gonna do.
我們已經造了一扇堅固的大門
We've already built a sturdy gate,
但是它還不夠堅固
but it's not quite sturdy enough.
所以我要把它釘出翔來
So I'm just gonna nail the crap out of it,
看看能否用這個方法將它們攔在外面
and we'll see whether I can hold them off that way.
讓它們的破牙盡情地咬吧
Let them sink their teeth into that.
又到了整集最精彩的時候了
This is the part of the episode where things get exciting.
準備好受死了嗎
Are you ready?
盡管來吧
Do your worst.
等哥叫人去
I'm coming back with friends.
我們對大門做了些加固
We did some door reinforcement, and now
現在  能否用集體的力量
as to whether or not we will be able to make it through this door
破門而入呢
with our collective amount of force,
我也不知道
I have no idea.
我實際上非常好奇
I'm actually really curious
杰米能加固到什么程度
about how good Jamie's reinforcements are
還有我們得使出多大的力氣
and how much power we can bring to bear.
真是太棒了
This is awesome.
停
Halt!
準備好了嗎  我數到三
Ready? On the count of three.
一  二  三
One, two, three!
停  我聽到有開裂的聲音了  等一下
Ugh! Hold! I heard some cracking. Hold on.
我們再試一次
We're gonna try that one more time.
還是老規矩
The same thing again.
一  二  三
One, two, three! Ugh!
停  再來一次
Hold! One more time.
我覺得我們可以破門的
I think we'll go through this door.
你死定了  海曼
You are meat, Hyneman.
等一下  三  二  一  走你
Hold on. Three, two, one. Go!
一  再來
one, go!
它擋住我們了
Oh! It's repelled us.
這對流言來說可不是好事
And that's bad news for the myth.
與電影中不同
Unlike the movies,
盡管發出了嘎吱破碎的聲音
despite all the creaking and cracking,
杰米的谷倉大門卻仍然屹立
Jamie's barn-door defenses are holding.
給我等著 老家伙
We're coming for you, old man.
但要說僵尸們有的一項特點
But if there's one thing zombies have got,
那就是堅持
it's persistence.
里面有大腦啊
There's brains in there!
三  二  一
Three! Two! One!
走你
Go!
它們雖然憤怒咆哮
Huff and puff they might...
好的  好的  推
Yes! Yes! Yes! Push!
但是大門完好如初
but the door remains tight.
杰米跳起了勝利的舞蹈
And Jamie does his victory dance.
他們進不來的
Never gonna happen.
僵尸們放棄了  杰米
Zombies give up, Jamie.
我們放棄了
We give up.
僵尸們  咱們回家吧
Zombies, let's go home!
僵尸們放棄了
The zombies give up.
杰米的防御奏效了
Jamie's defenses held up,
勝利者成功地活了下來  繼續對抗行尸走肉
and our victor lives to fight the living dead another day.
這門一開始真把我嚇壞了
The door was actually really frightening me.
它已經嚴重彎曲
It was bowing quite severely,
有些螺絲也冒了出來
and we had screws pop out.
而門軸也開始向內彎曲
The hinges themselves are starting to curl and come inward.
三  二  一  推啊
Three! Two! One! Go!
但是盡管變形彎曲  它卻沒有崩潰
But despite being compromised, it was never breached.
我得說
I have to tell you,
身處這次行動最前沿的位置
having been right there at the center of all the action,
有好幾次我都覺得我們要成功了
there was a couple of times I thought it was gonna give way.
但是盡管有很多木頭
But there was enough pieces of wood
出現了裂紋  開裂
that even with the cracking and the splitting
彎曲和拉伸
and the bending and the unrolling,
我還是能感覺到
I could still tell that
它能夠撐過今天
we could have battered on that all day long.
我們不可能成功的
We weren't gonna make it through.
那么我們對于
So where do we stand
僵尸集合力量的結論是什么呢
on the collective power of zombies?
若數量足夠  聚集起來確實增加了力量
Well, it does add up if you have enough of them,
但也力量也不是無窮的
but it's not limitless.
確實不是
No, it's not.
是的
Yep.
而隨著僵尸的力量總是能夠沖破
And with the myth that zombie-power can always pop
匆忙加固的大門這一流言被終結
your hastily reinforced portal well and truly busted,
死亡之日也到此結束了
The day of the dead is done.
知道什么讓我很高興嗎
Do you know what I'm really glad about?
-是什么  -就是僵尸根本不存在
- What's that? - That zombies don't exist.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
易燃
遠離明火
流言終結